SARAH K. RUSSELL

PROFILE

I've been working professionally as a Website Developer for over 16 years. I have a great passion for working in our ever changing industry. My bachelors degree in graphic design has given me a great resource; an eye for content layout and typography that I am able to apply to my website projects. Always excited to jump into a challenging new project or learn new skills. Excellent with mobile first, responsive design, HTML, CSS (Sass & Less), versioning (Git), ADA and Content Management Systems. Currently working with CSS Grid and Flexbox, while always expanding my knowledge of JavaScript and jQuery.

CONTACT

Greater Denver Area CONIFER, CO 80433

Email: sarah@skrdesign.com
Web: https://www.skrdesign.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarahrussell-a133049/

EXPERTISE

- Frontend Website Development
- HTML5
- CSS₃ / Sass / Less
- JavaScript / jQuery
- Mobile First
- Responsive design to work on desktop and mobile devices
- Git / GitHub / GitLab
- Code from scratch
- Bootstrap 4
- Foundation 6
- CMS systems
- Node
- Grunt / Gulp
- Command line
- Cross browser compatibility testing
- SEO optimization
- Adobe Creative Suite
- WCAG AA ADA Compliance
- Mac & Windows Systems
- Excellent communication
- Work in a team and individually
- Deliver on time

EXPERIENCE

Advanced Web Builder

PROFITSTARS (A JACK HENRY & ASSOCIATES COMPANY) REMOTE - CONIFER, CO / TEAM - NASHVILLE, TN

2014 - 2019

Hired after a six month contract. Worked in Nashville office until moving to Conifer in July of 2017.

Web Solutions team of project managers, designers, and builders overseen by managers. Work independently building responsive websites for banking and financial institutions based on the designer provided mockups (Adobe Illustrator and PDFs). Sites are built with either a Bootstrap or Foundation base, HTML5, CSS3 (Sass), JavaScript, jQuery, Git, Node, Gulp, and Grunt.

Built to meet WCAG AA ADA standards, cross browser and device compatibility tested, and added to a Content Management Systems (Episerver / RedDot / Banno) within project timelines.

Participated in code reviews of colleagues' websites. Web Builder Process Documentation team member.

Website Developer / Owner

SKR DESIGN LLC / CONIFER, CO

2003 - Present

Frontend website development company specializing in designing and building bespoke websites with a focus on reflecting the client's identity online within budget and on time. Handle all aspects of the project from design, branding, coding, hosting, launching and maintaining the site. Focus on building sites that reflect the client while providing a positive, easy to navigate experience for the user. For clients who want to update their own content, the site is added to a CMS.

Currently have five active clients; most have been with the company for over 9 years, while the newest client is under one year old. Clients are listed on the portfolio website with background on their website builds; https://www.skrdesign.com.

SARAH K. RUSSELL

PAGE TWO

EDUCATION

Bachelor's of Design – Visual Communications Design UNIVERSITY OF ALBERTA Edmonton, Alberta, Canada

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

Content Developer

ACXIOM / NASHVILLE, TN

2009 - 2014

Promoted from Content Specialist.

HTML specialist, responsible for; integrating, testing and approving high quality business to customer emails. Create emails that render responsively across browsers and mobile devices. Provide suggestions and recommendations directly to the client. Content lead for Sam's Club and American Cancer Society.

Group member; Platform Quality Assurance Group, Associate Satisfaction Survey Results Committee, and Acxiom's Nashville Office Events Committee.

INTERESTS

- Fly Fishing / Fly Tying
- World Traveling
- Skiing
- Kayaking
- Hiking
- Camping
- Backpacking
- Photography
- Board Games
- Knitting
- Reading

RECENT SITE BUILDS

SKR Design LLC - My portfolio site

https://www.skrdesign.com

January 2019

In January, this portfolio site was rebuilt to reflect the wonderful changes in our industry toward Flexbox and CSS Grid layouts. The homepage is a Flexbox layout, while the interior page layout was more suited to CSS Grid. The design concept came from a love of books. Books and websites are very much the same – a medium for information or telling a story. The mobile first, responsive site was built with a Foundation 6 base, Yarn, Sass, Flexbox and CSS Grid.

Central Bank of Kansas City

https://www.centralbankkc.com

April 2019

The site was a custom build while I was at ProfitStars. The designer provided Illustrator mock up files for me to reference. Mobile first, responsive site built with a Bootstrap 3 base, Node, Sass, JavaScript, jQuery, Flexbox, and Parallax homepage. Project version control with Git. Built to WCAG AA ADA standards, SEO optimized, cross browser and device tested. Added to a Content Management System for the client to make their own content updates.

Foothill Flyers Disc Golf Club

https://www.ffdgc.net

August 2019

I designed and built this mobile first, responsive site with a stripped down Foundation 6 base, Yarn, Sass, CSS Grid, Parallax homepage, and sticky navigation bar. Version control with Git, SEO optimized, WCAG AA ADA standards, cross browser and device tested. The client makes content updates with a Content Management System.

REFERENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST